Hello English learners. Welcome
back to English Pod. My name is Marco
and I'm Erica and today we'll
bring you part nine of our romantic
drama suspense action series. I'm sorry. I
love you. This is actually our penultimate
lesson. Exactly this story will end in part
10. So we're almost done. What's happening?
Well, I am pretty excited to
find out. So why don't we go
straight into the dialogue and
catch up with Stephen and Veronica.
Veronica, wait. Come on honey, get
back in the car. Let's talk it over, okay?
No. I'm tired of your lies. I
don't know who you are anymore.
Veronica, it's me. The man
that has and always will love you.
I'm sorry that I've
lied to you. Believe me.
It's been hard for me as well. And time and again,
I've thought of coming clean. But I couldn't put you
or my mission at risk. It's all over now. My assignment
is complete. And now I have to go back to India.
What are you kidding? Is there
anything else I should know
before I never see you again?
How could you deceive me like that?
Yes.
Veronica, I know that this isn't
the best time and you probably
hate me right now, but I want to
be completely forthright with you.
I know deep in my heart that you are the
best thing that has ever happened to me.
Veronica, would you marry me? Couldn't
we meet an India baby? I can't make
it for everything that's happened,
but I can promise you my undying love.
I will be the most devoted
husband and I will cherish you always.
Steven, I can't just leave
everything at the drop of a hat.
With everything that has happened
between us, I just don't know you anymore.
I just can't build a relationship
on a foundation of lies.
I do love you, but
I can't go with you.
I'm sorry. I love you.
This is the last call for flight 815
from Los Angeles to Hyderabad.
I'm sorry sir, we
can't wait any longer.
You must board the plane.
Are you waiting for someone?
I was, but I don't think she's coming.
Alright, so it seems like our poor
Steven is going home by himself.
Oh, it's so sad.
I know, he proposed she didn't accept and
now he's going back to India by himself.
You know, I think this must be
one of the worst feelings in the world.
Like, wondering if the
person you love is going to
show up at the last minute
and realizing they aren't.
I think it's very
common of movies.
You always expect the person
to come running and show up.
As you can see, our dialogues are more
realistic, so it didn't happen in this case.
More realistic. Okay. Anyway,
let's not debate that topic.
Let's go straight into the language
now with language takeaway.
Language takeaway.
Alright, so today on language
takeaway, we have six words that we're
going to be looking at and
let's get started with the first one.
Okay, so we've got language about
love and language about telling the truth.
And the first one is a
word about telling the truth.
So, Steven said, "I've
thought of coming clean.
" Okay, to come clean.
To come clean.
Now, if I want to come clean,
it means I want to admit to
something or to tell the truth
about something you've been hiding.
Exactly, okay, so I want to
finally tell the truth or confess.
So, someone needs to come clean about
who stole the chocolate out of the kitchen.
Okay, come clean. So, Steven
wanted to come clean on many
occasions, but Veronica said, "How
could you deceive me like that?"
Deceive someone.
How could you deceive me?
So, to deceive someone.
To deceive somebody. You make
them believe something that is untrue.
So, you kind of trick them.
Yeah, yeah.
Okay, make them believe or see
something that is not really true.
Exactly.
Alright, so that's the verb to deceive.
Now, the action of doing
this is called deception.
It was all a great deception.
Okay, so a big trick,
something a big untruth.
You deceived me.
Mm-hmm.
Alright, very good.
And now, the opposite of
deceive is to be forthright.
forthright.
So, Steven wants to be
completely forthright with Veronica.
Okay, I want to be forthright with you.
Alright, when you are
forthright with somebody,
you are very honest and
truthful with them, right?
Direct, tell them the truth
and everything directly.
And you don't like hide
it or soften it or anything.
Very good, so forthright.
Mm-hmm.
Alright, so three words about honesty.
Now, we've got three
words about love for you.
So, Steven promised
Veronica his undying love.
My undying love.
Now, undying.
Well, I think it's pretty easy, right?
It won't die.
It won't die, exactly.
So, he's offering her his love forever.
Mm-hmm, a very romantic phrase.
Very romantic.
And he also promised
to be a devoted husband.
Devoted husband.
I'll be the most devoted husband.
Now, this word devoted,
what am I saying there?
So, as a devoted husband, Steven
really, really would love his wife.
He'd really look after her
well and he would put all
of his energy into that,
into his marriage, right?
Okay, so he would be very committed to her.
Mm-hmm.
And work really hard.
Now, can I change the noun
husband for something else?
Yeah, we can talk about a devoted friend.
Or a devoted father.
Or a devoted employee.
Very good.
And our last word about love.
Well, Steven also promises
to cherish Veronica.
Okay, I will cherish you always.
I will cherish you always.
So, if I cherish somebody like my
girlfriend, what would that mean?
I mean, you hold her in your heart.
Like, you really love her
and you really respect
her and you hold
her close in your heart.
Okay, so I respect her and maybe
you don't take that person for granted.
Mm-hmm.
Okay, to cherish someone.
Yep.
All right, so some nice honesty
words, some nice love words.
And I think now we can move on to some
interesting phrases with fluency builder.
Fluency builder.
All right, so Veronica was upset.
She didn't want to get in the car.
And Steven said, let's talk it over, okay?
Let's talk it over.
To talk something over.
Now, if I tell you that I want
to talk it over, what am I saying?
Well, obviously you
want to talk about it, right?
But you want to talk
about it for sometimes.
To really talk about all of the
problems and the issues and everything.
So to try and make things clear.
Exactly.
All right.
And also when he was confessing, he said,
time and again, I thought of coming clean.
So this phrase time and again.
Time and again.
So that's basically the same as
saying again and again or many times.
Right.
So time and again, I've thought of quitting
smoking, but never really have done it.
So you've thought many times of doing it.
Mm-hmm.
Time and again.
Yep.
All right, so let's go to our next phrase.
Now, Veronica said, I can't just
leave everything at the drop of a hat.
At the drop of a hat.
So this is a very interesting and
colloquial way of saying immediately.
Mm-hmm.
So why don't we hear a few
examples of how this is used in English?
Example one.
My boss expects me to come
in to work at the drop of a hat.
Example two.
There's always willing to
help me at the drop of a hat.
Example three.
I can't leave at the drop of a hat.
I need time to prepare.
Okay.
So as you can see, you can
change it for different things.
But basically you're saying, I
can't do something immediately.
Yeah.
And it is almost always
attached to this idea of
doing something or going
somewhere, being somewhere.
Mm-hmm.
Very good.
At the drop of a hat.
All right.
Now our final phrase here for this lesson.
So Veronica was saying, I can't
go to India at the drop of a hat.
And she also said, I just can't build
a relationship on a foundation of lies.
Okay.
A foundation of lies.
To build something on a foundation of lies.
Now, this is interesting.
Let's take a look at this.
A foundation.
What is that?
Well, you know you have a house, right?
Mm-hmm.
And the part that's in the ground that
supports the house is the foundation.
Okay.
So it supports the entire structure.
Right.
So here she refers to
the lies as the foundation.
Mm-hmm.
And that's no way to start
a strong relationship, is it?
Exactly.
So we use it metaphorically
in this way, but
we can always, but we
always have to say it,
but we always have
to use the verb build.
Okay.
So it's basically to make something
on a base of something else, right?
Uh-huh.
So for example, a strong relationship
is built on a foundation of trust.
Or this country was built
on a foundation of liberty.
Very good.
So always use foundation with built.
Mm-hmm.
Very good.
Very interesting.
And, well, I think we should listen
to this dialogue before the last time.
And then we'll come back and talk a
little bit more about Veronica and Stephen.
Veronica, wait.
Come on, honey.
Get back in the car.
Let's talk it over, okay?
No.
I'm tired of your lies.
I don't know who you are anymore.
Veronica, it's me.
The man that has and always will love you.
I'm sorry that I've lied to you.
Believe me.
It's been hard for me as well.
And time and again, I've
thought of coming clean.
But I couldn't put you
or my mission at risk.
It's all over now.
My assignment is complete.
And now I have to go back to India.
What?
Are you kidding?
Is there anything else I should
know before I never see you again?
How could you deceive me like that?
Yes.
Veronica, I know that this isn't the best
time and you probably hate me right now,
but I want to be completely
forthright with you.
I know deep in my heart that you are the
best thing that has ever happened to me.
Veronica, will you marry me?
Come with me to India, baby.
I can't make it for
everything that's happened,
but I can promise
you my undying love.
I will be the most devoted
husband and I will cherish you always.
Steven, I can't just leave
everything in the drop of a hat.
With everything that has happened
between us, I just don't know you anymore.
I just can't build a relationship
on a foundation of lies.
I do love you, but I can't go with you.
I'm sorry.
I love you.
This is the last call for flight 8-15
from Los Angeles to Hyderabad.
I'm sorry, sir.
We can't wait any longer.
You must board the plane.
Are you waiting for someone?
I was, but I don't think she's coming.
So, Marco, I think I see a bit of a
tear there in the corner of your eye.
I'm very sad.
I can't believe he proposed
and she just said no, just like that.
It's not supposed to happen.
And plus, he was inviting her
to India and exotic getaway.
Well, exotic getaway
for the rest of her life.
Well, what do you think will happen?
Part 10, it all ends.
So do you think they all just
keep on living their separate lives?
Will they meet again?
Who knows?
Come to our website and tell
us what you think will happen.
So you can find us at EnglishPod.com.
Alright, don't miss
our finale of this lesson.
And until next time,
we'll see you guys there.